Manu Dwivedi manu29.d@gmail.com

Lead Software Engineer +91-8452866624

#### **Summary:**

Web Developer with ~9 years of experience with proficiency in full-stack development. Experienced in leading remote teams of developers and driving customer centric design and a healthy development culture. I have experience working with many growth-stage and established startups. I'm experienced in developing and maintaining scalable, extensible and reliable products. I believe myself to be highly analytical, empathetic and a curious team player. I love to teach and learn something everyday. I have been working with remote teams in the EST/CET time zones since 2014.

#### **Skills:**

Ruby	Javascript	Git
Ruby on Rails	NodeJS	REST API Design
PostgreSQL	React	Microservices
RSpec	TDD/BDD	Docker

#### **Work Experience:**

## Lead Software Engineer, PlanSource India (April 2021 - May 2022)

- Lead 4 teams in past year in different areas (BugBacklog Teams, Core Product, Technical Integrity)
- Responsible for performance monitoring, mentoring and training of developers in the team
- Responsible for goal setting, regular check-ins and reviewing achievements
- Facilitate cross-functional communication and development
- Contribute to Rails and React code base in the equal capacity as a senior developer
- Conducted training sessions on CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins and Samson & testing using MiniTest and RSpec
- Responsible for smooth functioning of Agile practices and maintaining coding standards in the team

# SDE-II Full Stack, Junglee Games India Pvt. Ltd. (Mar 2020 - Jan 2021)

- Worked on re-architecture and optimization of microservices in AWS
- POC on edge router implementation in Node Js using express js compliant middleware

# Senior Software Engineer, VYD Consulting Pvt Ltd (Mar 2017 - Apr 2019)

- Architect and lead contributor to multiple API projects
- 100% test coverage across all products in RSpec
- Setup containerized builds and deploys using Docker, CircleCI and git hooks
- Early employee, built culture and team from the ground up
- Led small teams across projects, mentor juniors
- Reduced CI build times by ~60%
- Coordinate releases while working remote with teams spread in 5 time zones (4 countries, 3 continents)

#### Senior Software Engineer, Talentica Software (Oct 2014 - Jan 2016)

- Individual contributor to multiple products
- Worked on Rails, Backbone, Angular and jQuery
- Worked as a lone contributor to project on GIS based systems using leaflet.js and Backbone

#### Software Engineer, Kreatio Software (Jun 2013 - Sep 2014)

- Worked on Rails 2,3,4
- Worked on upgrading legacy application from Rails 2 to Rails 4
- Worked as a lone contributor to new vertical in Smart Schools business
- Handled requirement gathering, software development and feedback cycle single-handedly
- Gave lectures on Rails, Ruby and Git

#### **Freelance Projects**

## **Software Developer, Turing Internal (Matching)**

React, Nodejs, NestJS, Prisma, chai, mocha

## **Technical Product Manager, Terra Analytics**

Hiring, Software Development, Architecture, BRD/PRD documentation

## Senior Software engineer, Tapchief

Lead design (Data Science Pipeline and Architecture), Python, Django

## Senior Software Engineer, Traco Tech

Full-stack engineer, Rails, React

#### Lead developer, Kingfisher #FlipToTheGoodTimes

Design to deployment, NodeJS, jQuery, websockets

## Lead Developer, Paintcollar

Angular, NodeJS

## Web developer, 3LOQ

Setup monitoring and altering system for big data infrastructure using Ganglia, NodeJS, Angular, CitusDB, D3

## **Academic Qualifications**

B.Tech, NIT Trichy, 2009-2013

## **Others**

- Development on AWS (certified course completed), Nov 2021
- How to Git gud, (guest lecture on git), Computer Society of India (DBIT, Mumbai)
- Industry mentor, Smart India Hackathon, Hyderabad and Mumbai
- 2nd runner-up, IBM-SwissRe hackathon, Bangalore